The ocean is calling them back.
Moana 2 is a animation, adventure, family film directed by David G. Derrick Jr..
After receiving an unexpected call from her wayfinding ancestors, Moana journeys alongside Maui and a new crew to the far
seas of Oceania and into dangerous, long-lost waters for an adventure unlike anything she's ever faced.
Moana (voice), played by Auliʻi Cravalho.
Maui (voice), played by Dwayne Johnson.
Moni (voice), played by Hualālai Chung.
Loto (voice), played by Rose Matafeo.
Kele (voice), played by David Fane.
Matangi (voice), played by Awhimai Fraser.
Moana 2 is a 2024 American animated musical adventure film
produced by Walt Disney Animation Studios.
The second film in the Moana franchise, it was directed by David Derrick Jr., Jason
Hand, and Dana Ledoux Miller and written by Miller and Jared Bush.
Cast members Dwayne Johnson, Auliʻi Cravalho, Rachel House, Temuera Morrison, Jemaine
Clement, Nicole Scherzinger and Alan Tudyk reprise their roles from the first film.
Set three years later, it follows Moana reuniting with the demigod Maui and assembling a wayfinding crew to
find the lost island of Motufetu, break its curse, and reconnect the people of the ocean.
A follow-up to Moana was originally developed as a miniseries for Disney+, but
by February 2024 it had been reworked into a theatrical sequel.
Mark Mancina and Opetaia Foaʻi, the composers and co-songwriters of the first film, returned to score
and write the songs, while Abigail Barlow and Emily Bear provided additional songs.
Moana 2 premiered at the Lanikuhonua Cultural Institute in Kapolei, Hawaii, on November 21, 2024, and
was released by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures in the United States on November 27.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $1.059 billion worldwide,
outgrossing its predecessor and becoming the third highest-grossing film of 2024.
It was nominated for Best Animated Feature Film at the 82nd Golden Globe Awards.
The film explores themes of sea, ocean, villain, musical, sequel.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting.